Animation Number 1
Calling
Senjougahara Hitagi
What is it, Kaiki... So late at night?
（戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)）
何よ？　貝木(かいき)　こんな時間に
（貝木）仕事の報告だ
I'm reporting about my job. Can you step out for a bit while the trains are still running?
まだ電車が動いているうちに
戦場ヶ原
ちょっと出てきてくれるか？
Huh?
（貝木）会って話したいことがある
There's something I'd like to talk about in person. As soon as possible.
できるだけ早くだ
All right.
（戦場ヶ原）
分かったわ
言いなりになってあげるわよ
I'll do as you say. I'm your dog.
私は あなたの犬よ
少なくとも
今から２か月半の間はね
At least for the next two and a half months.
（貝木）ハハ それはいいな
That's a great idea.
（戦場ヶ原）
ふん
You know, Kaiki, there's one thing I'd like you to tell me.
ねえ 貝木
１つ教えてほしいのだけれど
女子高生を
好き勝手にできるというのは
As a middle-aged man, how does it feel to be able to have your way with a high-school girl?
中年男性としては
どういう気分なのかしら？
（貝木）そうだな
Let's see.
At the least, it's not a bad thing to watch a spoiled brat...
少なくとも 生意気なガキが
身の程を わきまえて
従順に こうべを垂れる姿は
...knowing her place and obediently hanging her head down.
見ていて悪いものではないな
Senjougahara Hitagi
（戦場ヶ原）
死ね
Die.
Hitagi End          Part Three
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
Ticket Barrier
Fire Hydrant
Good evening, Kaiki. I didn't recognize you for an instant because you had your hair down.
Central Ticket Barrier
Central                            Ticket Barrier
（戦場ヶ原）こんばんは 貝木
髪を下ろしているから
一瞬あなただと分からなかったわ
そういう服を着ていると
You look like a decent human if you wear clothes of that sort.
まるで まともな人間みたいね
And what about you? Why are you wearing your uniform even though it's night?
（貝木）そういう お前は
どうして 夜なのに
制服を着ているんだ？
I want to show you as little as possible of my private fashion closet.
Central Ticket Barrier
Central                            Ticket Barrier
（戦場ヶ原）あなたに できる限り
私のプライベートファッションを
見せたくないのよ
By wearing my uniform, I'm asserting that I'm seeing you only from a business perspective.
あくまで仕事上の関係で
会っているだけということを
私は制服を着ることで
主張しているの
Are there any family restaurants in this area?
Recruiting
（貝木）
この辺りにファミレスはあるか？
What, you were planning on escorting a lady without even reserving a place first?
（戦場ヶ原）なによ
あなた
レディーをエスコートするのに
店の予約もしていないの？
I'm pretty uncouth and unaware of the world...
Fire Hydrant
（貝木）
俺は かなり やぼで
世間知らずな男だがな
...but when I escort a lady, of course I reserve a place.
レディーをエスコートするときには
当然 店の予約をする
So that's not something I need to do now.
だから 今はしていないわけだ
This way.
Recruiting
こっちよ
Senjougahara did not guide me to a family restaurant, but rather to a Mr. Donut fast food restaurant.
Animation Number 62
Hot Dog    115
Beef   115
Shrimp    115
Apple        115
Cream         115
Honey       115
Chocolate        115
Plain    115
Extra Dark Chocolate    115
Extra White Chocolate    115
Strawberry 50 Yen
Honey 50 Yen
Sugar 50 Yen
Chocolate 50 Yen
Filled 50 Yen
Winter Sale Ongoing
Special
Winter
Donuts
First
Floor
I'll just have some water. Kaiki, you should order something.
私は水を飲むから
貝木 あなた何か頼みなさいよ
I could buy you something.
Hiring Part-Timers
おごってやってもいいぞ
That's a bad joke.
（戦場ヶ原）悪い冗談ね
Even if it wasn't a joke, I don't want you to treat me to anything.
冗談じゃなかったとしても
あなたに おごられるなんて
ごめんよ
Then, pay me back the flight fare from yesterday right now.
Winter Sale Ongoing
Special
Winter
Donuts
First
Floor
（貝木）
だったら
今すぐ昨日の飛行機代を払えよ
Come to think of it, I paid for all the drinks at the cafe yesterday too...
そういえば喫茶店での飲み物代も
結局 俺が払ったんだったよな
That's something...
（戦場ヶ原）それは…
...I'd like a bit more time for.
（戦場ヶ原）
もう少し待ってください
Shouldn't you think a bit before you talk?
Winter Sale Ongoing
Special
Winter
Donuts
First
Floor
（貝木）
お前 もう少し 後先考えて
発言したほうがいいんじゃないか？
I'm sure you talked to Sengoku Nadeko like that without much thought.
どうせ そんなふうに考えなしに
千石撫子(せんごくなでこ)とも話したんだろうよ
Why aren't you taking that hot-looking thing off?
お前
なんで
その辺の暑そうなのを脱がないんだ
脱げよ うっとうしい
Take it off. It's annoying me.
Though I'm away from my town, the chance that someone I know will see us isn't that low...
（戦場ヶ原）
町を離れているとはいえ
知り合いに見られる可能性も
低くはないというか…
だから…
So...
Why don't you be honest with Araragi and talk to him about this?
（貝木）いっそ
阿良々木(あららぎ)に 正直に話してしまえば
いいんじゃないのか？
If you were frank yet polite, and explained it to him logically without becoming emotional...
お前が懇切丁寧に感情的にならず
理論立てて説明すれば
それでも嫌がるほどの
分からず屋ではないだろう
...he can't be so square-headed that he'd still be against it.
That's true, but...
（戦場ヶ原）そうだけれど
I think Araragi-kun has a misunderstanding about my relationship with you.
阿良々木くんは
私と あなたとの関係を
誤解している節もあるから
Misunderstanding?
誤解？
He's got the mistaken notion that you were my first crush.
（戦場ヶ原）
あなたが私の初恋の相手だと
勘違いしているのよ
Because back then you made a lie you didn't have to, or rather, one you made with malice...
あのとき あなたが余計な…
というか
悪意のあるウソをついたから
Well, sorry about that.
そりゃあ 悪かったな
You were only deceived by me and toyed around to my liking.
お前は 俺に だまされて
いいように
弄ばれただけなのに
You know, Senjougahara. I want to ask you something.
なあ 戦場ヶ原
１つ聞きたいのだが
What?
（戦場ヶ原）何よ？
（貝木）
お前
こういうふうに食事をしている際
When you're eating out like this...
席を外すときに
かばんを持っていくか？
...do you take your bag when you leave your seat?
Huh? What's this all of a sudden?
は？　なによ いきなり
少なくとも
At the least, I'd take it with me when I'm eating a meal with you.
あなたと食事をしているときには
持っていくかしらね
Don't assume it's me.
俺を想定するな
Let's see... For example, earlier today you were celebrating the new year at Araragi's house.
そうだな 例えば今日
お前は阿良々木家で
正月を祝ったということだが
そのとき 俺との電話とかで
廊下に出るとき
Did you take your bag with you when you stepped into the hallway to answer my call?
自分のかばんを持って出たか？
Of course not. Not even I would do something that rude.
出るわけないでしょ
（戦場ヶ原）
いくら私でも
そんな失礼なこと しないわよ
Hmm. Well, that's probably true.
ふむ　まあ そうだろうな
Why are you asking something like that all of a sudden?
（戦場ヶ原）
なんで 出し抜けに
そんなことを聞くの？
You know, Sengoku Nadeko was probably the type...
（貝木）いや 千石撫子は
そういうときに
ちゃんと かばんを持って
出るヤツだったんだろうなと
...that would take her bag with her in times like that. I think.
思って
That was the impression I had of Sengoku Nadeko when I met her today.
それが今日
俺が千石撫子に会っての
感想なわけだが
You were able to meet Sengoku Nadeko? Today? Just now? Out of the blue?
（戦場ヶ原）千石撫子に会えたの？
今日 さっき いきなり？
It's that easy to meet her? Though imperfect, a god?
そんな簡単に会えるものなの？
曲がりなりにも神様に？
That's impossible, or are you really a...
そんなこと…
それとも やっぱり
あなた本物の…
I'm a fake. You already know that.
俺は
偽物だよ 知ってるだろ
She never trusted anyone, never believed in anyone...
あいつは誰も信用することなく
誰も信じることもできず
...during the 13 or 14 years of her life. That's what I thought.
13年だか14年だかを
生きてきたんだろうな
そう思った
That's not really so. At the least, from what I've heard, she completely trusted Araragi.
（戦場ヶ原）そんなことないわよ
少なくとも聞いた限りでは
阿良々木くんのことは
全面的に信用していたみたいよ
If that really was true, none of this would have happened.
（貝木）
もしも
本当にそうだったのなら
こんなことには
なってないさ
Please see
Tomiaki-san
at the
shrine
office
Please see
Tomiaki-san
at the
shrine
office
Those who
haven't...
please
do not
proceed
beyond
this
point.
Those who
haven't...
please
do not
proceed
beyond
this
point.
Polar
Well, Araragi is at fault for that. There is no room for him to make excuses.
まあ その件に関しては
阿良々木が悪い
釈明の余地なくな
You're covering for Sengoku Nadeko an awful lot.
随分と千石撫子をかばうじゃない
It can't be. Don't tell me you were...
まさか あなた実際に会ってみて
あの子のかわいさに
...charmed by her "cuteness" now that you've actually met her?
すっかり篭絡されたと
いうんじゃないでしょうね
Huh? I was?
は？　俺がか？
Right... I guess that would never happen.
（戦場ヶ原）
ええ それはないわよね
すみませんでした
全面的に非を認めます
I'm sorry. I'll admit fault there.
Actually, hearing you sincerely apologize about this like that makes me feel unpleasant.
（貝木）
この件で
そこまで真摯に謝られると
逆に不愉快だと
言わざるをえないが…
なあ 戦場ヶ原
Well, Senjougahara...
あの娘 千石撫子が
Certainly that girl, Sengoku Nadeko, was in an environment that induces sympathy.
同情を誘う環境にあることは
確かだったよ
Sympathy?
同情？
Even I sympathized a bit. But that's a story of the past.
俺も同情くらいはしたよ
しかし それは昔の話であって
She seems to be enjoying her current condition, so it shouldn't matter.
今は わりと
楽しそうにやってるみたいだし
どうでもいいだろう
Senjougahara, you can rest assured for now.
戦場ヶ原
（貝木）とりあえず安心していい
（戦場ヶ原）え？
Huh?
It's really easy to deceive that girl.
あの娘をだますのは
たやすい
Animation Number 177
It's easy? What do you mean?
たやすいって どういうこと？
To say that deceiving such a dangerous existence — a snake god surpassing human limits — is easy?
あんな危険な存在を
人間を超越した蛇神(へびがみ)を
だますことが
たやすいだなんて
If it was something that simple, I wouldn't take my time to request your services.
そんな簡単なことなら
私は わざわざ
あなたに依頼なんてしないわ
Well, it would be impossible for you, and impossible for Araragi too.
（貝木）まあ お前には無理だよ
阿良々木にも無理だ
But for anyone else, I think it would be possible. Even if it weren't me.
だが それ以外の人間なら
俺でなくとも可能だとは思うぞ
Sengoku Nadeko... That girl is an airhead.
千石撫子 あいつはバカだ
I'm not saying her grades in school are bad,
Animation Number 190
or, well, of course those are bad too—
People probably kept overlooking her foolishness and naivete for all this time.
多分 愚かさや稚拙さを
ずっと見逃され続けて
きたのだろう
年齢以上に幼い
She's very immature for her age.
Kept overlooking...
（戦場ヶ原）
見逃され続けてきた…
Because of her cuteness?
Animation Number 196
I plan on frequenting that shrine from now on...
（貝木）
俺は これから
あの神社に通って
千石撫子と
...and I'll keep communicating with Sengoku Nadeko to win her trust.
コミュニケーションを
取りつつ
信用を勝ち取りながら
And around next month, I'll tell her that you and Araragi were in a traffic accident and died.
そして来月くらいか
お前と阿良々木が
交通事故にでも遭って
死んだと伝える
That should solve everything.
それで解決だ
Solve?
解決って…
But normally, if she heard something like that...
でも 普通に考えたら
そんなことを聞かされたら
...wouldn't Sengoku Nadeko first confirm our mortality with her own eyes?
千石撫子は 私たちの生死を
自分の目で確認するんじゃないの？
She won't.
（貝木）確認しない
She won't confirm it.
あいつは確認しない
She'll take it at face value.
そのまま うのみにする
How can you be so positive about it?
（戦場ヶ原）
どうして そこまで断言できるの？
I can tell by talking to her.
（貝木）話してみりゃ分かる
She's been spoiled way too much, so she's too dependent on others' kindness.
ありゃあ
甘やかされ過ぎていて
甘え過ぎていて
Basically, the thought of someone deceiving her or lying to her never enters her mind.
他人が自分をだましたり
ウソをついたりすることを
基本的に想定していない
She can't believe in people, but she also has no need to doubt people.
人を信じられない代わりに
人を疑う必要もない
そういう環境で育っている
That was the environment she grew up in.
Essentially, she's a sheltered princess.
Animation Number 216
You said she was an indirect victim of the fraud I set up six months ago...
（貝木）
俺が半年前に仕掛けた詐欺の
間接的な被害者だということだが
...but maybe she herself thinks it was some kind of mistake?
しかし 本人は案外
ひょっとしたら何かの間違いだと
思ってるんじゃないか？
About why she would be the target of such a charm... Of such a curse...
自分が そんな おまじない
“呪い”の対象になるだなんて
In other words, she's been dulled to malice.
要は悪意に鈍いってことね
Though, that said, thinking about the risks if I fail...
（貝木）
まあ… とはいえ
失敗したときのリスクを考えると
...it's still hard to say this is an easy job.
やっぱり ちょろい仕事だとは
言い難いがな
On the one-in-a-million chance she sees through me, I don't think I'll stay alive.
万が一にも看破されたら
俺は生きてはいられないだろう
Especially because she is dull to malice...
悪意に鈍いからこそ
だからこそ
ちょっとした悪意や
普通ならば看過できるような害悪を
...she can't possibly ignore the smallest bit of malice or ill will that would normally be passed by.
きっと あいつはスルーできない
Because she can't and couldn't ignore things...
（戦場ヶ原）スルーできず
スルーできなかったから
阿良々木くんや私を
...she's trying to kill me and Araragi.
殺そうとしているというわけね
Sengoku Nadeko is stuck on you, conversely, due to a feeling that shallow.
（貝木）
千石撫子が
お前に拘泥しているのは
逆に言えば
その程度の気持ちでしかない
I suppose, being in the second year of middle school, she is a child after all...
Animation Number 235
By becoming a deity, it seems that Nadeko has further regressed into immaturity.
（貝木）
千石撫子は神様化することで
むしろ幼児化しているようだ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Right... Maybe the word to use here is reincarnated.
（貝木）そう…
生まれ変わったとでも言うのかな
Will she possibly end up being a better god than expected?
案外 あいつは
いい神様になるんじゃないか？
Though, she probably needs to calm down a little more...
もちろん
神様としての威厳を出すためには
...to assume the bearing of a god.
もう少し落ち着きが必要だろうが
So rest assured. You guys are probably spared for the most part.
だから 安心しろ
おおよそ お前たちは助かった
Good for you. You won't have to die.
よかったな 死なずに済むぞ
Sidewalk
Do not park your vehicles
You'll be a college student come spring.
春からは花の大学生というわけだ
You can make out with Araragi as much as you want. You can live a life of debauchery.
好きなだけ
阿良々木と いちゃつけるぞ
Main St.
ただれた生活を送れるぞ
Stop
Well, the problem is how to tell Araragi that everything has been resolved.
まあ 問題は阿良々木に
事が解決したというのを
どういうふうに伝えるかだよな
Considering the misunderstanding he has now,
あいつがしているという
誤解を思うと
we can't possibly tell him that I deceived Nadeko.
まさか 正直に
俺が千石撫子をだましたとは
言えないだろうし
What do you think you're doing? I thought you didn't want me to treat you.
何のまねだ
俺に おごられるのは
嫌なんじゃなかったのか？
If I steal from you, it's okay.
（戦場ヶ原）
強奪する分には いいのよ
Those are strange standards.
（貝木）変わった基準だな
I'll do something about Araragi-kun.
阿良々木くんのことは
私が なんとかするわ
あなたを煩わせることはない
There's no need to trouble you.
I'll convince him somehow and have Araragi-kun give up on Sengoku Nadeko.
なんとか説得して
阿良々木くんには千石撫子のことを
諦めてもらうしかない
そこを諦めないからこそ
阿良々木くんなんだけれど…
Though it wouldn't be Araragi-kun, the man I fell in love with, if he didn't quit even then.
私の ほれた男なんだけれど
Here's a good way.
（貝木）いい方法があるぞ
You should make Araragi choose by asking him, "Who is more important? Me or Sengoku Nadeko?"
阿良々木に
“私と千石撫子
どっちのほうが大事なのよ”と
選択を迫るんだ
If you could be such an annoying woman,
お前が そういう
うっとうしい女になれば
he'd have no choice but to give up pursuing Sengoku Nadeko.
あいつは さすがに
千石撫子を諦めるだろうぜ
Excuse me.
（戦場ヶ原）失礼
Animation Number 271
She took her bag with her. Good attitude.
Animation Number 272
She does manage to impress me.
Sorry to make you wait.
（戦場ヶ原）お待たせ
Kaiki...
貝木
Thank you. I appreciate it.
ありがとう 感謝するわ
Animation Number 280
Senjougahara Hitagi was finally able to relax for the first time.
（貝木）
戦場ヶ原ひたぎは
ようやく
気を緩めることができたのだろう
Of course, if it was just about her...
無論 それでも
自分のことだけだったのなら
...she would have been stubborn and not cried over it.
意地を張って
あの女は泣かなかったかもしれない
だが 恋人の命まで
助かったとなれば
But because it meant her lover's life was also spared, she couldn't help but cry about it.
泣かずには
いられなかったのだろう
That's the type of girl she is.
そういう女だ
She's a fool like that.
そういうバカだ
The only problem is the expense to do this.
やっかいなのは経費のほうかな
10,000 yen each time I go visit...
１度会うたびに１万円とか
Sengoku Nadeko.
Animation Number 293
She's a greedy one.
With what remains of my expenses, I can't even go see her five more times.
必要経費の残金じゃ
あと５回も会いに行けないぜ
Animation Number 295
Okumei Bookstore
Parking Spots
7            Children's Literature
Cat's
Cradle
All right, I memorized them.
よし 覚えた
Yay! Onii-chan! Peace, peace!
（斧乃木(おののき)）
いえーい おにいちゃん
ピース ピース
She's got a new tick.
Animation Number 308
Bad influence from her friends, I bet.
Animation Number 309
It's been a while, Kaiki-oniichan. How long has it been?
久しぶりだね 貝木おにいちゃん
いつ以来かな
Don't call me Onii-chan.
（貝木）
おにいちゃんなどという
呼び方をするな
Yay!
いえーい
Perhaps she got close to Araragi.
Animation Number 315
What happened to Kagenui?
影縫(かげぬい)のヤツは どうした？
ひょっとして
この辺りに来ているのか？
Perhaps she's somewhere around here?
（斧乃木）ううん お姉ちゃんは…
No, she is...
Whoa. That was supposed to be a secret.
おっと これは秘密なんだっけ
Secret?
秘密？
It means I can't tell you.
内緒という意味だよ
But, that said, you're supposed to be keeping an eye on Kagenui, right?
（貝木）
しかし そうは言っても
お前は影縫の監視役だろう
斧乃木
お前は 一体 何をやっているんだ？
Ononoki, what the hell are you doing right now?
（斧乃木）
僕は あなたに来たんだよ
I came to you.
I came to see you.
僕は あなたに会いに来たんだよ
On an errand from Gaen-san.
臥煙(がえん)さんの使いでね
（貝木）臥煙？
Gaen?
Gaen Izuko.
Animation Number 328
A warning from Gaen-san.
臥煙さんから忠告
No. Wait. I don't want to hear it. Don't say anything.
（貝木）いや 待て
聞きたくない 言うな
She said, "Pull out."
（斧乃木）手を引けってさ
Pull out?
（貝木）手を引け？
いえーい
Yeah!
"Someone like you should not meddle with that town."
“お前のような人間が”
“その町を かき乱すな”
“イレギュラーはあったが”
"There were a few irregularities, but that town is now somewhat stable."
“その町は今
ある程度 安定している”
"Kaiki, if you do something unnecessary, it will all go to waste."
“貝木
お前が余計なことをしたら”
〝台無しになる
というか〞
"Or rather, it will be worse than before. So, pull out."
〝元より ひどくなる〞
“だから手を引け”
Peace, peace!
ピース ピース
Did Gaen-senpai really say that last bit? Or is that how your character is lately?
（貝木）
最後のは臥煙先輩が言ったのか？
それとも お前の最近のキャラか？
It's how my character is lately.
最近の僕のキャラだよ
I see. Say it again and I'll punch you away.
そうか
今度言ったら ぶっ飛ばすからな
I threatened her.
Animation Number 345
I must seem like Araragi now.
Do you have anything else you want to drink?
何か追加で飲みたいものはあるか？
（斧乃木）貝木
Kaiki. You're saying things like you were devil boy.
まるで鬼のおにいちゃん
みたいなことを言うね
Looks like we're similar in more ways than one.
Animation Number 347
This is embarrassing.
New
year
Big
sale
I still have a drink, so I'm fine, but... Let's see...
飲み物は
まだあるからいいけれど
Happy New Year
New Year's sale
そうだね
I want to eat a chocolate chunk scone, warmed up.
僕は
チョコレートチャンクスコーンの
Treasure
温めたやつが食べたいな
You insulted me by saying I was like Araragi. You really think I'd buy you something now?
人を阿良々木のようだと
侮辱しておいて
おごってもらえるとでも思うのか
I don't need any change.
釣りはいらないよ
I appreciate your efforts.
ご苦労
（貝木）ふん
Gaen-senpai seems to understand me, yet doesn't understand me that much.
臥煙先輩は
俺のことを分かっているようで
案外 分かっていないな
How troublesome.
困ったもんだ
If I'm told to pull out, I'm going to be more gung-ho about finishing it, of course.
手を引けなんて言われたら
俺は むしろ やる気を出すに
決まっているだろう
She said she'd pay if necessary.
なんなら金を払うと言っていたよ
Three million yen.
300万円
Thirty Minutes Later
Animation Number 372
I decline. Don't think of me so cheaply.
お断りだな あまり人を安く見るな
Go back and tell her she's off by at least a digit.
桁が１桁は違うんじゃないのかと
伝え返せ
Unfortunately, at this point, I can't contact Gaen-san anymore.
（斧乃木）
残念ながら 現時点では僕はもう
臥煙さんとは連絡が取れないんでね
If you want to tell her, tell her yourself, Kaiki-oniichan.
言いたければ自分で言ってよ
貝木おにいちゃん
Kaiki...
貝木
In other words...
要するにさ
...I think Gaen-san is worrying about what would happen if you fail your job, Kaiki.
貝木の仕事が
失敗したケースのことを
臥煙さんは
心配しているんだと思うんだよね
Kaiki, you're trying to fool Sengoku Nadeko, right?
貝木は千石撫子を
だまそうとしているんだろう？
Well, I don't know about that.
さ〜て どうだったかな
（斧乃木）
うん 多分それは成功するんだ
Yeah, I think that will succeed.
貝木ほどの才覚があれば
With as much talent as you, Kaiki... Well, even without that much...
いや 多分なくっても
...deceiving that girl is easy.
あの子をだますことは
たやすい
But the risk involved if you were to fail is just too high.
だけど失敗したときのリスクが
高すぎるってことさ
Right now, Nadeko has enough godly powers to easily destroy an entire town.
今の千石撫子は
町くらいなら あっさり滅ぼせる
神通力を持っている
Well, as a spoiler...
まあ ネタばれしちゃうとさ
そもそも あの町を
...Gaen-san is the one who's trying to straighten that town out in the first place.
頑張って
ちゃんとしようとしているのが
臥煙さんってことになるのかな
The original plans didn't have the human named Sengoku Nadeko becoming a god.
本来 千石撫子という人間が
神様になる予定はなかった
Gaen-san's original plans had that old hag...
臥煙さんの当初の計画としては
後期高齢者…
No, wait, what was she?
（斧乃木）
じゃない　えっと 何だっけ？
She was planning to make the one that was previously...
（斧乃木）
旧キスショット･アセロラオリオン･
ハートアンダーブレードを
あの人は神様にするつもりだった
みたいなんだよ
...Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade, into a god.
That vampire had been treated as a god once before, so she was fit for the job.
（斧乃木）
あの吸血鬼は
一度は神様扱いされているから
まあ 適役だったんだろうけど
But due to some mistake... For some reason, someone intervened.
何かのミスというか
なぜか誰かの介入があったらしくて
And that job was transferred over to Sengoku Nadeko.
その役目が
千石撫子に移行したというか
（貝木）ふ〜ん
The current situation is not one that Gaen-san sought.
（斧乃木）
今の状況は 決して
臥煙さんが望んだものではない
However... Still, it's not a terribly bad situation either, for sure.
けれど でも
それほど悪くない状況であることも
確かなんだそうだ
Wash your heart and body before visiting the gods
How to
wash
your
hands
How to
wash
your
hands
1. put a ladle
of water on
your left hand
2. next on your
right hand
3. hold a little water in your
left hand, and rinse your
mouth. Cover your mouth
with your
hand when
you spit it
out
4. wash your left
hand again,
since it touched
your mouth
5. finally
wash the
ladle's
handle
with the
water left
This way the next person can do the same easily.
Care for each other!
Y...
...ay.
えーい…
There's one message I forgot to tell you.
１つ 忘れていた伝言を思い出した
"If you don't plan on pulling out, I am no longer your senpai. Our relationship as such is over."
“もしも手を引かないのであれば”
〝お前とはもう〞
〝先輩でもなければ
後輩でもない〞
What will you do, Kaiki-oniichan?
どうする？　貝木おにいちゃん
I'll think about it.
（貝木）
俺は考える
さっきも 一度考えたが
さっきよりも深く考える
I thought about it for a moment earlier, but this time I put in a bit more thought.
I remembered Senjougahara's cried-out face I saw last night.
ゆうべ見た
戦場ヶ原の泣きはらした顔
And her words of thanks. The words of thanks directed at none other than me.
そして お礼の言葉を
ほかでもない俺に対して言った
お礼の言葉を思い出す
Then, my relationship and interests with Gaen-senpai.
それから臥煙先輩との関係
利害関係
I was reminded of the proposed sum of three million yen.
300万円という
提示された額を思い出す
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Ononoki.
（貝木）
斧乃木
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
All right. I'll pull out.
分かった 手を引こう
Animation Number 426
Stop
Of course, I had no intention of pulling out.
（貝木）
当然 手を引くつもりなどなく
After I received the three million yen from Ononoki...
俺は斧乃木から
300万円を受け取ってから
そのまま その足で
北白蛇(きたしらへび)神社へと向かった
...I headed straight over to North Shirahebi Shrine.
Of course, I turned Gaen-senpai into one of my enemies in return.
無論 その代償として
臥煙先輩を敵に回してしまったが
But come to think of it, she was like an enemy to begin with.
考えてみれば
もともと敵みたいな人だったので
むしろ これで縁が切れて
さっぱりしたような気分だった
Once my ties to her were gone, I felt slightly refreshed.
Here's Nadeko!
（千石）撫子だよ〜！
Oh, Kaiki-san! You came!
あ！　貝木さん 来てくれたんだ
（貝木）そりゃ まあ
Of course. I am your number one adherent.
お前の信者 第１号だからな
Actually, I have a wish that I really, really want granted.
（貝木）実は
俺には すごくすごくかなえたい
願いがあるんだよ
So I decided to do the hundred times worship here at this shrine.
だから この神社に
お百度参りってやつを
することにしたのさ
A hundred times worship, huh?
お百度参りか〜
I did that once too maybe... Maybe not?
撫子も したことが…
あったような なかったような？
And, what's your wish, Kaiki-san? Is it something I can grant?
で 貝木さんの お願いって何？
撫子に かなえられること？
Well, it's hard to say in one phrase.
さ〜て ひと言では
言いづらいのだが
But if I were forced to summarize it in one phrase, I'd say "prosperous business."
まあ それでも
無理やり ひと言で言うならば
商売繁盛ってところかな
Prosperous business...
しょうばいはんじょう？
Well, from here on I'm going to be here...
（貝木）まあ これから100回
...100, or to be more precise, 98 more times.
厳密に言えば あと98回
俺は ここに来るんだ
There's no need to rush. I'll tell you in due time.
慌てる必要はない
おいおい話していくさ
うん！　そうだね
Yeah! That's true!
You can tell me about yourself bit by bit, Kaiki-san!
少しずつ教えてね
貝木さんのこと！
I'll listen! I'm a god!
撫子 聞くから
神様だから！
So, for today, teach me some cat's cradle! Like you promised!
で 今日は とりあえず
あや取りを教えてよ
約束どおり！
I've already mastered basically all of the ones you taught me yesterday!
昨日教えてもらった技は
大体 全部マスターしちゃったんだ
Cat's cradle, huh? All right. Pull out the rope I gave you yesterday.
（貝木）あや取りね
いいだろう
昨日やった あや取りを出せ
Oh, that? It snapped because I was playing nonstop.
ああ あれは ずっと遊んでたら
切れちゃったんだ
So I used this instead to practice.
だから
これで代わりに練習してたんだよ
So, show me, show me, Kaiki-san!
ね！　やって やって 貝木さん
This girl is not only stupid, she's also insane.
（貝木）
この娘はバカで しかも狂っている
North
Shira
hebi
Shrine
North
Shira
hebi
Shrine
She's an airhead. And she's lost her marbles.
頭が悪く 頭がおかしい
Animation Number 458
I felt like someone was shadowing me for a while after I came down the mountain.
尾行されているな と気付いたのは
山を下り
それから
しばらくしてからのことだった
The most probable theory is, of course, one of Gaen-senpai's "henchmen."
いちばん可能性があるのは
当然 臥煙先輩の下っ端という線だ
The next most probable theory is perhaps a junior high kid who has a grudge against me.
で 次に高いのは
俺に恨みを持つ中学生かな
But, in that case, they're more likely to show...
Fare  411530 Yen
Number   564832
Freeway          En Route                                     Wait             Discount            Select            Forward
ただ その場合
いきなり後ろから
どつくなり何なり
...a more direct method of violence, such as a sudden assault from behind.
直接的な暴力に
打って出そうなものだ
Sir, are you a traveler?
（運転手）
お客さん 旅行者ですか？
Well, kinda.
ええ まあ
（運転手）
どうですか？　この辺りは
How is it around here?
It's pretty fun.
楽しいですね
いろいろスリリングで
Thrilling in all sorts of ways.
Animation Number 474
In the end, I didn't get on a train from the station that the taxi dropped me off at...
（貝木）
結局タクシーで
送ってもらった駅から
電車に乗ることもなく
...nor did I go back to my hotel.
Stop
ホテルに戻ることもなく
I headed straight back into the town I had just left.
そのまま とんぼ帰りで
俺は元の町へと戻った
I wasn't worried about whoever was shadowing me.
尾行を警戒したのではない
I had already completely stopped thinking about that.
それはもう
完全に気にするのをやめた
それよりも
気にするべきことがあった
There was something more worthy of my attention.
The manner in which Sengoku Nadeko had been broken.
千石撫子の壊れ方だ
"I found something that looked like a clue concerning my missing daughter."
“失踪した娘の 手がかりの
ようなものが見つかった”
"It's not something I can talk about over the phone...
“電話で話せるような
ことではなく”
...and I'd like to hear your opinion as well."
“あなたたちの判断も
お聞きしたいので”
"So can you come by the location I'm going to specify now?"
“今から言う場所に
来ていただけないか”
というようなことを
とても遠回しに
Or something like that, in a very roundabout way.
In other words, in a very reserved manner...
つまり遠慮気味に
...but weaving in a fair bit of inability to refuse, I tell them.
しかし それなりの断りづらさを
織り込みつつ
俺は言う
Now...
（貝木）さ〜て
What the hell is this!
何だ こりゃ？
Preview
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Karen here!
（火憐(かれん)）
火憐だぜ！
And Tsukihi!
I'm Tsukihi!
（月火(つきひ)）
月火だよ！
Together, we're the Fire Sisters!
We're the Fire Sisters!!
Love!
（２人）
２人合わせて
ファイヤーシスターズ！
I shouldn't let
my sisters get involved...
What should I do
If we were gravelling we could be the Camp Fire Sisters!
（月火）
旅行に行けば
キャンプファイヤー
シスターズだよ
（火憐）
そりゃあ 良好だな
That's travelling...
（月火）
予告編ク〜イズ！
Preview Quiz!
（火憐）
ク〜イズ！
Quiz!
I hear computers are a lot better than humans at playing shogi.
（月火）
将棋でコンピューターは
もう人より強いって
いうじゃない？
I know! I'll make
some flyers to advertise her.
Yeah, as a human being it's beyond frustrating.
（火憐）
いうな〜
人間としては
悔しい限りだぜ
Well, I don't agree with that.
（月火）
だけど
私はそうは思わない
You don't find this frustrating?
（火憐）
悔しくないのか？
Not that, I don't think computers are better than humans.
（月火）
じゃなくて
コンピューターが将棋で
人より強いとは思えない
So many visitors all of a sudden!
Oh, and why is that?
（火憐）
そりゃまた どうして？
Computers can't move, promote or capture pieces on their own,
（月火）
だって あいつ自分で
駒 動かさないじゃん
駒 裏返さないじゃん
駒 取らないじゃん
Look! Sisters! This was the solution!
Pay a visit to the cute God!
Eh!
in the end it's us humans who do all the moving on the board.
盤上の駒を動かすのは
結局 人なわけでしょ！
（火憐）
いや そうだけど…
Yeah, but...
I'm saying that until they can manipulate pieces, computers can go back where they came from.
（月火）
マニピュレーターを
装備してから
出直してこいと
私は言うね
Next time! Koimonogatari Episode 4!
Next Time
Hitagi End Part 4
（２人）
次回「恋物語 第４話
ひたぎエンド 其ノ肆(そのよん)」
Hitagi End, Part 4.
Nadeko will never come back!
Chomp
By the way Tsukihi-chan, can you play shogi?
（火憐）
ところで月火ちゃん
将棋知ってんの？
I only know the very basics.
（月火）
たしなまない程度には